TYLER TWITCHELL

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

169 Diamond Street, Brooklyn, NY 11222 tytwitchell@gmail.com
(631) 553-1639

Portfolio: tylertwitchell.netlify.app
Github: github.com/tytwitchell
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tytwitchell

I am a software engineer with eight years of professional work experience as a consultant and a focus on building easy-to-use applications that solve problems. I value environments where empathy, self-awareness, and taking initiative are expected, and I take pride in my ability to learn and work with others.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Van Morph Tool (Work in progress)

React.js, React Router 6, Firestore Database

- This application streamlines one of my client's time consuming daily tasks. He manages a daycare center
 and his employees drive shuttle vans to pick up the participants. When an employee is out of office, the
 application reassigns their passengers to vans with similar routes and available seats.
- GitHub: https://github.com/tytwitchell/van-morph
- Completed:
 - o Created a form to add new vans to the database.
 - o Developed "drag and drop" UI that enables the user to move passengers manually from one van to another.
 - o Enabled the user to select an out of office employee.
- In Progress:
 - o Add logic that assigns passengers from the out of office employee's van to other vans based on capacity and proximity to route.

Quizzical

React.js, Open Trivia Database API

- A trivia app that allows the user to choose a category and drops confetti if at least 4/5 questions were answered correctly.
- URL: <u>quizzical-tt.netlify.app</u>
- GitHub: github.com/tytwitchell/Quizzical

Tenzies

React. js, CSS, HTML

- A game where the user rolls dice until all of them are the same. The game tracks the amount of rolls and time spent playing to create a competitive feel.
- URL: tenziesgame-tt.netlify.app
- GitHub: github.com/tytwitchell/TenziesGame

KEY SKILLS

- React.js
- JSX
- JavaScript

- CSS
- HTML
- Effective communication and teamwork

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Project Management: Atlassian Confluence / JIRA
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Code Collaboration: Code Reviews, Collaborative Projects
- Web Development Tools: VS Code, Chrome DevTools, Figma
- HRIS Software: Rippling, Namely, Gusto, ADP, Ease, Workday

EDUCATION

Scrimba Bootcamp

Frontend Web Developer, October 2023

University at Buffalo

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, December 2015

Concentration: Finance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bennie Insurance LLC, New York, NY

Benefits Consultant

November 2021 - July 2023

- Communicated intricate technical benefit concepts to client stakeholders, including CFOs, HR managers, and employees
- Led Bennie App demonstrations for employees, enhancing understanding of app capabilities
- Built and managed benefit plans efficiently on various HRIS software platforms
- Created reusable Excel templates, streamlining repetitive tasks and improving client service
- Facilitated cross-departmental collaboration, ensuring timely project completion
- Managed projects to ensure timely completion of deliverables
- Developed and presented in-depth benefit marketing campaigns to mitigate insurance renewal premiums

Namely Inc, New York, NY

March 2018 - November 2021

Technical Benefits Consultant

- Provided technical troubleshooting of the HRIS and payroll platforms for HR managers
- Created new systems and processes to better service clients using Excel
- Collaborated with client human resource teams and finance departments to ensure compliance with government regulations and company policies
- Proposed and implemented innovative strategies for enhancing client culture through Namely technology and benefit offerings
- Led and prepared client renewal and benefit strategy presentations

Benefits Analyst

- Supported five consultants in maintaining relationships with clients
- Developed underwriting analysis based on the previous 12-24 months of client claims data
- Analyzed existing benefits programs for cost effectiveness and compliance with applicable laws

Arthur J. Gallagher & Co., Jericho, NY

March 2016 - March 2018

Benefits Analyst

- One of three key employees to assist in the implementation of a branch-wide document management system
- Discussed and implemented strategies to mitigate risk and enhance overall client business performance